<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Feature Lists (Explanation)</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
          <div xml:id="tunocentExplanationFeatures" xml:space="preserve">
              <head>Feature Lists (Explanation)</head>
              
              <p xml:space="preserve">The feature list is a standardised questionnaire that focuses on grammatical and lexical variation. 
                  It consists of linguistic features in lists of sentence pairs in English and Arabic that are meant to exemplify selected 
                  salient linguistic features of the particular varieties. Generally, the feature lists allow the website users to get a 
                  quick impression of a particular variety. The usage of the same sentences/features as in the general VICAV site, allows 
                  for optimal comparisons not only between the varieties recorded within TUNOCENT but also with the wider range of Arabic 
                  varieties recorded in <ref target="https://vicav.acdh.oeaw.ac.at">VICAV</ref>. 
                  The categories contained in the feature lists include phonological, morphological 
                  and lexical features, which are <hi rendition="#i">Interrogatives, Pronouns, Presentatives, Adverbs, Numerals, Adjectives, Colours, Prepositions, 
                  Important Verbs, Nouns, Neologisms, Modality,</hi> and <hi rendition="#i">Other Items</hi>. The respective feature is marked in red. </p>
              
              <p xml:space="preserve">Words highlighted in yellow inform the user about various details:
<list> <item>1) that the highlighted word or construction is a non-dialectal form, i.e. either a loan from Standard Arabic, from the prestigious variety spoken in the capital of Tunis or a mixed form.</item> 
<item>2) that it is a French word.</item>
<item>3) that the highlighted word or construction was spoken by a speaker different from the identifier(s) given in the beginning of the text. </item>
<item>4) it can inform about a sociolinguistic value given by the respective speaker: ‘OLD’ would mean that the highlighted form is primarily used by old 
    people or that it used to be common before and that it has fallen out of use. ‘YOUNG’, on the contrary, provides the information that a given form is 
    preferentially used by young speakers. Characterising a form with the label ‘RURAL’ means that it is primarily found in the speech of rural speakers, i.e. 
    those who live in the countryside in small villages, but that urban speakers residing in towns would prefer a different form.</item>
</list>
Two words in brackets separated by a slash, like  (ā-hāw / hā-hāw), are variants provided by the speaker during the interview.
</p>
              
              <p xml:space="preserve">This section includes several functions to search and display the feature lists in different ways. The feature lists can be 
                  displayed both as a list sorted by their governorate, and on the map according to their location. Additionally, in the function <hi rendition="#i">Search and compare feature 
                  lists</hi> the data can be filtered by a number of categories, such as place, feature, and speaker, to provide the user with the opportunity to search for specific 
                  sets of data. Moreover, by clicking on a word the user is provided with an inventory of all feature lists that contain this particular word. </p>
              
              <p xml:space="preserve">The website contains 195 features lists: 31 for locations within the governorate of Beja, 14 for Jendouba, 16 for Siliana, 36 for Kef, 19 for Sidi Bouzid, 
                  4 for Kairouan, 40 for Kasserine and 35 for Gafsa. This means, that for obtaining the feature lists at least 195 different speakers were interviewed. To some feature lists 
                  more than just one speaker contributed, which makes the number of speakers rise to some 220.</p>
              
          </div>
          
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
