<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>TUNOCENT Conference</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p xml:space="preserve">Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p xml:space="preserve">Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <ab></ab>
         </projectDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:id="tunocent_conference">
            <head>Conference Organisation 2022</head>
            <div>

               <head>Revisiting traditional isoglosses in the Maghreb:
                  Methodology | Terminology | Classification; Algeria | Tunisia |
                  Libya</head>
               <p>Online conference organised by</p>

               <p><hi rendition="#i">Veronika Ritt-Benmimoun</hi>
               <lb/><hi rendition="#i">Karlheinz Mörth</hi>
                  <lb/><hi rendition="#i">Aleksandra Naddari</hi>
                  <lb/><hi rendition="#i">Ghaith Naddari</hi></p>

               <p> 2nd and 3rd June 2022</p>
               
               <figure>
                  <link target="Sbiba1.jpg"/>
                  <graphic url="Sbiba1.jpg"/>
                                 </figure>
            </div>
            
            <div>
               <head>Invitation to the Conference</head>
               <p>In April 2019 we started our FWF-funded project titled Tunisia’s Linguistic terra
                  incognita: An Investigation into the Arabic Varieties of Northwestern and Central
                  Tunisia (TUNOCENT) in cooperation with the Austrian Academy of Sciences (ÖAW). In
                  this project we want to provide up-to-date linguistic data for the hitherto almost
                  unknown Arabic varieties spoken in the region approximating the seven Tunisian
                  governorates of Jendouba, Beja, Kef, Siliana, Kasserine, Sidi Bouzid, and Gafsa. This
                  region can be viewed as a unit because of its shared socio-linguistic (Bedouin-type
                  dialects), socio-historical (semi-nomadism and sedentarization), socio-economic (weak
                  economy, high unemployment, emigration), and topographical (mainly mountainous)
                  character.</p>
               <p>In 1950 the famous French dialectologist William Marçais affixed the term terra
                  incognita - W. Marçais (1950:212) used the term 'ignota' instead (W. Marçais. 1950. “Les parlers arabes.” In: A. Basset (ed.) Initiation
                  à la Tunisie. Paris, 195-219) - to Tunisian Bedouin-type dialects, differentiating them into what he called
                  the H- (Hilāl) and S- (Sulaym) dialects. His judgement that further research into these
                  almost completely unknown varieties is urgently needed still holds true now, almost
                  70 years later - G. Mion (2015: 270)writes of “En absence complète d’analyses sur la région intérieure du pays …” (G. Mion. 2015.
                  “Réflexions sur la catégorie des «parlers villageois» en arabe tunisien.” Romano-Arabica XV, 269-277). Therefore, this project is the first attempt to linguistically illuminate a
                  part of Tunisia which has long remained under-studied.</p>
               
               <p>Now after almost three years of our project we want to look back to the first phases of
                  our work that involved the recording and collecting of the linguistic data, as well as the
                  transcription of certain questionnaires. Before starting the intensive task of describing,
                  comparing and classifying these dialects, a discussion with experts on various fields of
                  Maghrebi dialectology should enable a fruitful future work in this project.</p>
               
               <p>This discussion should take place in the realm of an online-symposion organised by the
                  Department of Near Eastern Studies of the University of Vienna in cooperation with
                  the Austrian Centre for Digital Humanities and Cultural Heritage (ACDH-CH) of the
                  Austrian Academy of Sciences. It will feature two (or probably three) days of
                  presentations and discussions (2nd and 3rd of June 2022) and will take place online with
                  the conference tool Zoom. Since you are one of the specialists in this particular field of
                  Arabic dialectology we would like to invite you to participate in this conference.</p>
               
               <p>For many regions of the Maghreb we still rely on classifications and categorizations
                  that are almost hundred years old (e.g. those of William Marçais and Jean Cantineau).
                  In the realm of our symposion we want to challenge the isoglosses that were mainly of
                  phonological and morphological nature and investigate their significance in the
                  modern linguistic landscape. As is well known, syntax has often been neglected in
                  dialect studies and not been considered for isoglosses as it demands large corpora that
                  are often not available to researchers. Our conference should stress the importance of
                  (morpho-)syntactic phenomena for classifying dialects. To mention only a few, the role
                  that agreement patterns, the use of the genitive marker and the dual, progressive markers, auxiliary verbs, subordinate clauses play in individual dialects and as possible
                  isoglosses should be investigated.</p>
               
               <p>The conference should improve our understanding of the complex relationship
                  between the Tunisian dialects and those spoken in adjacent areas of Algeria and Libya.
                  It should also provide new insights into the diachronic and synchronic linguistic
                  situation in the central Maghreb.</p>
               
               
               <p>Papers can touch on all fields of Arabic dialectology concerned with Tunisia, Algeria
                  and Libya, and also relevant aspects dealing with digital approaches to Arabic
                  dialectology:
                  <lb/>- Questioning of traditional isoglosses, traditional terminology and traditional
                  dialectal classifications
                  <lb/>- Syntactic characteristics as isoglosses
                  <lb/>- Phonological, morphological and syntactic aspects of Tunisian, Algerian and
                  Libyan Arabic dialects
                  <lb/>- Diachronic and synchronic aspects of various Tunisian, Algerian and Libyan
                  dialects
                  <lb/>- Descriptions of hitherto little or non-investigated Tunisian, Algerian and Libyan
                  dialects
                  <lb/>- Bedouin and sedentary dialects in comparison
                  <lb/>- Youth language versus dialects of the older generations and other sociolinguistic
                  aspects
                  <lb/>- Dialect geography
                  <lb/>- Methodological questions
                  <lb/>- Development of koiné languages and prestige dialects
                  <lb/>- Lexicon of Tunisian, Algerian and Libyan dialects
                  <lb/>- Tunisian, Algerian, and Libyan dialects in their broader Maghrebinian context
                  <lb/>- Digital humanities and Arabic dialects</p>
               
               <!--  <p><ref target="https://gitlab.oeaw.ac.at/acdh-ch/tunocent/tunocent-content/vicav_texts/TUNOCENT-Symposion_Programme.pdf">Programme</ref></p>-->
               
            </div>

         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
