<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:space="preserve">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Profiles (Explanation)</title>
                <title type="shortTitle">PROFILES</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Publication Information</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Information about the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
          <projectDesc>
              <ab>The links for the profiles were assembled by scriptor.exe--&lt;createListOfVICAVProfiles</ab>
          </projectDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:id="tunocentExplanationProfiles" n="PROFILE">
                <head>Profiles</head>
                <p xml:space="preserve">In our endeavour to collect and document information about Tunisian Arabic varieties, 
                    it was important to us to also collect information about the places where we conducted our field research and obtained language recordings. 
                    This is because the geographic, demographic, historic and economic circumstances of an interviewee’s places of birth and residence can be 
                    important factors for the analysis of their speech. In order to make this information available to the users of our website, we created a 
                    <hi rendition="#i"> profile </hi> for most of the locations where we recorded our data. These profiles contain concise general portrayals of each place, often describing 
                    briefly its geography and history and most notable sights, demographics, and the inhabitants’ prevalent way of life and main means of income. 
                    Furthermore, information on tribal subgroups as well as local saints are found in the profiles, as they are important pillars for the people’s identity. 
                    The pictures included in the profiles - all of them taken by the project’s field researchers - show the landscape and the villages of Northwestern 
                    and Central Tunisia and give insight into the way people live. As such, they are valuable ethnographic witnesses of the people’s traditional 
                    activities which the interviewees also describe in the recorded texts. </p>
                <p xml:space="preserve">In addition, each profile offers a brief insight into the research history of the Arabic variety that is spoken in the place it describes. 
                    Links to the sample texts and the feature lists lead the website users on to speech samples of the respective location. Thus, the profiles provide the reader with a
                    well-rounded impression of each place and serve not only as a way to present valuable sociolinguistic data, but also as a way for the website user to dive into Tunisia’s diverse culture.</p>
                <p xml:space="preserve">The website contains 71 profiles: 11 in the governorate of Beja, 7 in Jendouba, 7 in Siliana, 10 in Kef, 11 in Sidi Bouzid, 2 in Kairouan, 
                    14 in Kasserine and 9 in Gafsa. They can be displayed either as a list sorted by their governorate or on the map.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>













