<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:space="preserve">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sample Texts (Explanation)</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
          <div xml:id="tunocentExplanationSampleTexts">
              <head>Sample Texts (Explanation)</head>
              
              <p xml:space="preserve">The sample texts are translations of the same source text. Of course, these translations vary (slightly) 
                  depending on the differences between the various Tunisian Arabic varieties. Thus, they provide an easy way to compare the 
                  numerous linguistic phenomena contained in the texts. The use of the same source text as in the general VICAV site, allows 
                  for optimal comparisons not only between the varieties recorded within TUNOCENT but also with the wider range of Arabic 
                  varieties recorded in <ref target="https://vicav.acdh.oeaw.ac.at">VICAV</ref>.</p>
              <p xml:space="preserve">The sample text is composed of seven sentences or units which provide details on everyday activities 
                  and duties, and as such contain important basic vocabulary: shopping in the market, different fruits and vegetables, returning 
                  home, having lunch with the family, asking the children about their plans for the rest of the day and for future activities.</p>
               <p xml:space="preserve">Words highlighted in yellow inform the user about various details:
<list> <item>1) that the highlighted word or construction is a non-dialectal form, i.e. either a loan from Standard Arabic, from the prestigious variety spoken in the capital of Tunis or a mixed form.</item> 
<item>2) that it is a French word.</item>
<item>3) that the highlighted word or construction was spoken by a speaker different from the identifier(s) given in the beginning of the text. </item>
<item>4) it can inform about a sociolinguistic value given by the respective speaker: ‘OLD’ would mean that the highlighted form is primarily used by old 
    people or that it used to be common before and that it has fallen out of use. ‘YOUNG’, on the contrary, provides the information that a given form is 
    preferentially used by young speakers. Characterising a form with the label ‘RURAL’ means that it is primarily found in the speech of rural speakers, i.e. 
    those who live in the countryside in small villages, but that urban speakers residing in towns would prefer a different form.</item>
</list>
Two words in brackets separated by a slash, like  (ā-hāw / hā-hāw), are variants provided by the speaker during the interview.
</p>
              <p xml:space="preserve">This section includes several functions to search and display the sample texts in different ways. They can be displayed both
                  as a list sorted by their governorate, and on the map according to their location. Additionally, in the function <hi rendition="#i">Search and compare sample texts</hi> 
                  the data can be filtered by a number of categories, such as place, sentence number, and speaker to provide the user with the opportunity to search 
                  for specific sets of data. Moreover, by clicking on a word the user is provided with an inventory of all sample texts that contain this particular word. </p>
              <p xml:space="preserve">The website contains 185 sample texts: 26 for locations within the governorate of Beja, 11 for Jendouba, 20 for Siliana, 34 for Kef, 
                  17 for Sidi Bouzid, 4 for Kairouan, 37 for Kasserine and 36 for Gafsa. This means that for obtaining the feature lists at least 195 different speakers were interviewed. 
                  To some sample texts more than just one speaker contributed, which makes the number of speakers rise to some 200.</p>
              <p xml:space="preserve">For 18 <!-- CHECK THIS NUMBER --> sample texts audio recordings are available on this website <!-- LINK -->.</p>
              <p>The source text from which the sample texts were translated is:</p>
              <p>Modern Standard Arabic: <quote>يوم الاثنين بعد الفجر ذهبتُ إلى السوق لأشتري بيضا وخضروات مثل الباذنجان والثوم.
واشتريت أيضا 2 كيلو برتقال بـ [مبلغ مناسب في العملة المحلية] ولكن لم آخذ طماطم لأنه كان غاليا جدا.
مررت بأخي الكبير وبعدها ركبتُ تاكسي وعُدت إلى البيت قبل الظهر.
بعد قليل جاء الأولاد من المدرسة وأكلنا [أكلة تونسية].
بعد الغداء سألتهم قائلة: ماذا تفعلون المساء.
قالوا لي: اليوم نبقى في البيت ولكن غدا نريد أن نرى أصدقاءنا وسنذهب معهم إلى ابن خالتنا الذي يسكن في حي [اسم أي حي في المدينة أو القرية] وهناك سوف نشرب قهوة ونتحادث إن شاء الله.
!قلت لهم: طيب، ولكن لا تنسوا أن تأخذوا معكم هواتفكم وأخبِروني إن تأخرتم
</quote></p>
<p>English: <quote>On Monday after dawn I went to the market to buy eggs and vegetables such as aubergines and garlic. 
I also bought 2 kilograms of oranges for (price in local currency).
I didn’t take tomatoes because they were very expensive.
I passed by my elder brother, then I took a taxi and came back home before noon.
A little later the kids returned from school and we ate (local meal).
After lunch I asked them, “What will you do this evening?”
They said to me, “Today we’ll stay at home but tomorrow we want to meet our friends.
We’ll go with them to our cousin, who lives in the … neighbourhood.
There, God willing, we’ll drink coffee and talk a little.”
I said to them, “Okay, but don’t forget to take your mobile phones with you and call me if you come back late”.

</quote></p>
          </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
