<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Explanation Data Types</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
          <div xml:id="tunocentExplanationDataTypes" xml:space="preserve">
              <head>Explanation Data Types</head>
              
                       
              <div>
                  <head>Profiles</head>
              
              <p xml:space="preserve">Profiles are general portrayals of chosen locations where fieldwork was conducted, often describing briefly their geography, history and most notable sights, 
                  demographics, and the inhabitants’ prevalent way of life and main means of income. Furthermore, information on tribal subgroups as well as local saints are found in the profiles, 
                  as they are important pillars for the people’s identity. The pictures included in the profiles - all of them taken by the project’s field researchers - show the landscape and the 
                  villages of northwestern and central Tunisia and give insight into the way people live. As such, they are valuable ethnographic witnesses of the people’s traditional activities 
                  which the interviewees also describe in the recorded texts. </p>
                  
              </div>
          
          <div>
             <head>Sample Texts</head> 
              <p xml:space="preserve">The sample texts are translations of the same source text. This text is composed of seven sentences or units which provide details on everyday activities and duties, 
                  and as such contain important basic vocabulary: shopping in the market, different fruits and vegetables, returning home, having lunch with the family, asking the children about their 
                  plans for the rest of the day and for future activities. Thus, they provide an easy way to compare the numerous linguistic phenomena contained in the texts. The use of the same source text 
                  as in the general VICAV site, allows for optimal comparisons not only between the varieties recorded within TUNOCENT but also with the wider range of Arabic 
                  varieties recorded in <ref target="https://vicav.acdh.oeaw.ac.at">VICAV</ref>.
</p>
          </div>
          
          <div>
              <head>Corpus Texts</head>
              <p xml:space="preserve">The corpus texts, also called free speech texts or unmonitored speech, include narratives, ethnographic texts and conversations recorded during the numerous fieldwork trips 
                  in the regions of northwestern and central Tunisia. In addition to the transcribed corpus texts on the TUNOCENT-webpage which are extracts from already published research, about 60 to 70 hours 
                  of speech were transcribed in the course of the project but have not been published yet. Together, these published and to-be-published corpus texts form the largest text collection in scientific 
                  transcription to exist for Tunisian dialects.</p>
                 
                 </div>
          <div>
              <head>Feature Lists</head>
              <p xml:space="preserve">The feature list is a standardised questionnaire that focuses on grammatical and lexical variation. It consists of linguistic features in lists of sentence pairs in English 
                  and Arabic that are meant to exemplify selected salient linguistic features of the particular varieties. The categories contained in the feature lists include phonological, morphological and 
                  lexical features, which are Interrogatives, Pronouns, Presentatives, Adverbs, Numerals, Adjectives, Colours, Prepositions, Important Verbs, Nouns, Neologisms, Modality, and Other Items. 
                  The usage of the same sentences/features allows for optimal comparisons between the varieties recorded within the TUNOCENT-project. The usage of the same sentences/features as in the general 
                  VICAV site, allows for optimal comparisons not only between the varieties recorded within TUNOCENT but also with the wider range of Arabic 
                  varieties recorded in <ref target="https://vicav.acdh.oeaw.ac.at">VICAV</ref>.</p>
                  
          </div>
          
          <div>
              <head>TUNOCENT-Questionnaire</head>
              <p>This is a detailed and extensive questionnaire which brings together the most important phonological, morphological, syntactic and lexical peculiarities of the varieties spoken in the various 
                  reference points. It is a comprehensive tool for the synthesis and analysis of the linguistic data. Though not digitalised yet, these questionnaires have been used for the description of the 
                  varieties spoken in Testour and Nefza, for the shorter dialect sketches, as well as for the comparative research undertaken and published in the course of the project.</p>
          </div>
          
          <div>
              <head>WAD-Questionnaire</head>
              <p>This is a lexical questionnaire kindly provided for use by the authors of the monumental "Wortatlas der arabischen Dialekte" (WAD), Peter Behnstedt and Manfred Woidich. With 500 lexical items 
                  it covers the most important semantic categories of relevance for Arabic dialects. Though not digitalised yet, these questionnaires have been used for the description of the varieties spoken 
                  in Testour and Nefza, for the shorter dialect sketches, as well as for the comparative research undertaken and published in the course of the project.</p>
          </div>
          </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
