<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Vicav Contributors</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p xml:space="preserve">Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p xml:space="preserve">Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
          <projectDesc>
              <ab>The links for the profiles were assembled by scriptor.exe--&lt;createListOfVICAVProfiles</ab>
          </projectDesc>
      </encodingDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
	<div xml:id="tunocent_about">
		<head>
			TUNOCENT
		</head>

		<p xml:space="preserve">(April 2019 → September 2024)</p>
		<p xml:space="preserve">
			funded by
			<ref target="https://www.fwf.ac.at/en/">
				The Austrian Science Fund
			</ref> (FWF)
		</p>
		<p xml:space="preserve">The project “<hi rendition="#b">Tu</hi>nisia’s Linguistic <hi rendition="#i">terra incognita</hi>: An
			Investigation into the Arabic Varieties of <hi rendition="#b">No</hi>rthwestern and
				<hi rendition="#b">Cent</hi>ral Tunisia (TUNOCENT)” aims at the collection, documentation
			and analysis of dialectal varieties in the northwestern and central Tunisian
			governorates:</p>
			
		<p xml:space="preserve">Under the leadership of <ref target="mailto:tunocent@oeaw.ac.at">Veronika Ritt-Benmimoun</ref>
			from the Department of Oriental Studies, <ref target="https://orientalistik.univie.ac.at/en/">University of Vienna</ref> and in
			cooperation with the national research partner Karlheinz Mörth from the <ref target="https://www.oeaw.ac.at/acdh//">Centre for Digital Humanities
				and Cultural Heritage of the Austrian Academy of Sciences</ref>, a <ref target="https://tunocent.acdh.oeaw.ac.at/team/">team of three field researchers
			</ref>from the University of Vienna contributes to the TUNOCENT project. <ref target="https://www.fwf.ac.at/en/">The Austrian Science Fund</ref> (FWF) finances the
			investigation, for which a period of four years was determined, starting in April 2019.
			For latest information about our research status as well as current developments, check the
				<ref target="https://tunocent.acdh.oeaw.ac.at/category/news/">News</ref> section.</p>
		<div xml:id="background">
				<head>
					The Background
				</head>
				<p xml:space="preserve"><hi rendition="#b"> – What is the deeper motive of this research? – </hi><lb/>In 1950,
					the famous French dialectologist William Marçais affixed the term “terra
					incognita” to Tunisian Bedouin-type dialects, differentiating them into what he
					called the H- (Hilal) and S- (Sulaym) dialects. His judgement that further
					research into these almost completely unknown varieties is urgently needed still
					holds true now, almost 70 years later. Therefore, this project is the first
					attempt to linguistically illuminate a part of Tunisia which has long remained
					understudied, in contrast to some dialects spoken along the coast.</p>
				<p xml:space="preserve"><!--EndFragment--></p>
				<p xml:space="preserve"><hi rendition="#b"> – And what should be the outcome? – </hi>
					<lb/>Our project promises to be a giant stride in our knowledge of Tunisia’s
					linguistic landscape, and will be of great importance for an understanding of
					the complex relationship between the Tunisian dialects and those spoken in
					adjacent areas of Algeria and Libya. It will also provide new insights into the
					diachronic and synchronic linguistic situation in the central Maghreb.</p>
		</div>
		<div>
		<head>
			The Approach
		</head>
		<p xml:space="preserve"><hi rendition="#b">– How do we work? – </hi>
			<lb/><hi rendition="#b">The first phase </hi>of the project will involve the recording and
			collecting of linguistic data through fieldwork using mainly qualitative methods,
			considering the relevant diatopic and diastratic parameters. <lb/><hi rendition="#b">In the second
				phase, </hi>selected dialects will be categorised and two varieties representing
			the main dialectal areas described in detail. Intra-dialectal comparison will reveal the
			common traits and differences of Tunisian Bedouin-type dialects and should enable a
			detailed classification of them, something which has hitherto never been undertaken. The
			shared history of (semi)nomadism and the current social reality of settlement will allow
			us to consider how “Bedouin” these dialects are and whether some of them have gone
			through a process of urbanization.<lb/><hi rendition="#b">Ultimately</hi> a digital and fully
			searchable corpus of transcribed and translated narrative and ethnographic texts and
			conversations will be built. This corpus and the gathered data will be hosted at the <ref target="https://www.oeaw.ac.at/acdh/">Austrian Centre for Digital Humanities and
				Cultural Heritage (Austrian Academy of Sciences).</ref> This will ensure both open
			access and long-term preservation of our data.</p>
		</div>
		<div>
		<head>Cooperations</head>
		<p xml:space="preserve">Through cooperation agreements we profit from the scientific experience, knowledge and
			contacts of our national and international partners:</p>
		<list>
			<item xml:space="preserve"><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="https://www.unica.it/unica/it/ateneo_s07_ss01.page?contentId=SHD160628"
						>Giuliano Mion</ref> (Italy)</hi>: expert in Tunisian Arabic, <ref target="https://www.unica.it/unica/en/homepage.page">University of Cagliari
					(UniCa)</ref></item>
			<item xml:space="preserve"><hi rendition="#b"><ref target="http://www.inalco.fr/enseignant-chercheur/christophe-pereira"
						>Christophe Pereira</ref> (France)</hi>: specialist in the Arabic of
				Tripoli in Libya</item>
			<item xml:space="preserve"><hi rendition="#b">Dominique Caubet (France): </hi>leading expert on Maghrebi-Arabic, <ref target="https://www.inalco.fr/en">Institut National des
					Langues et Civilisations Orientales (INALCO)</ref></item>
			<item xml:space="preserve"><hi rendition="#b">Lameen Souag (France):</hi> director of <ref target="https://lacito.cnrs.fr/en/directory/lameen-souag/">LACITO (CNRS)</ref> and
				specialist in Algerian Arabic</item>
			<item xml:space="preserve"><hi rendition="#b">Hager Ben Ammar (Tunisia): </hi>Standard and Tunisian Arabic teacher;
				member of the <hi rendition="#i">Association Derja</hi>; publisher of several books written in
				Tunisian Arabic and a textbook on Tunisian Arabic (<hi rendition="#i">Parler tunisien fissa! Une
					méthode originale pour apprendre l’arabe tunisien en 6 mois</hi> with co-author
				Valérie Vacchiani, 2016)</item>
			<item xml:space="preserve"><hi rendition="#b">Moez Maataoui (Tunisia): </hi>senior assistant at the Department of
				Linguistics (Faculté des Lettres, des Arts et des Humanités) at the <ref target="http://www.uma.tn/">University of Manouba</ref></item>
			<item xml:space="preserve"><hi rendition="#b">Stephan Procházka (Austria): </hi>internationally renowned expert on
				Arabic dialects, professor of Arabic Studies at the <ref target="https://orientalistik.univie.ac.at/en/">Department of Near Eastern Studies of
					the University of Vienna</ref>, and highly experienced with third-funded projects,
				e.g. as project leader of <ref target="https://tunico.acdh.oeaw.ac.at">TUNICO <hi rendition="#i">–
						Linguistic dynamics in the Greater Tunis Area</hi></ref></item>
		</list>
		</div>
	<!-- .entry-content -->
</div>
</body>
</text>
</TEI>
