<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Corpus (Explanation)</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
          <div xml:id="tunocentExplanationCorpus" xml:space="preserve">
              <head>Corpus (Explanation)</head>
              
              <p xml:space="preserve">The corpus texts, also called free speech texts or unmonitored speech, include narratives, ethnographic texts and conversations recorded 
                  during the numerous fieldwork trips in the regions of northwestern and central Tunisia. In addition to the transcribed corpus texts on the TUNOCENT-webpage 
                  which are extracts from already published research, about 60 to 70 hours of speech were transcribed in the course of the project but have not been published yet. 
                  Together, these published and to-be-published corpus texts form the largest text collection in scientific transcription to exist for Tunisian dialects</p>
              
              <p xml:space="preserve">This section includes two main ways to display the corpus texts: Starting from the complete list of corpus texts which is arranged geographically 
                  according to governorates, the respective texts can be chosen and are presented in transcription unit by unit. Some of the texts are accompanied by an audio file. 
                  In the function “Search the corpus” the user can either search for specific words or make an advanced search. Moreover, by clicking on a word the user is provided with 
                  an inventory of all units that contain this particular word. The respective words, which are presented within the context of the unit they occur in, are marked in bold.
</p>
              
             <p xml:space="preserve">The website contains 24 corpus texts: 14 for locations within the governorate of Beja, 2 for the governorate of Kef, 7 for the governorate 
                 of Kasserine and 1 for Sidi Bouzid.</p>
          </div>
          
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
